Edgar Colón Barrientos

Senior Software Engineer

- Ubicación: Ciudad de México

Email: edgar.colonb@gmail.com

Web: https://edgar-colon.mx/

- Phone: (+52) 7444328340

- Age: **34 years old**

SUMMARY

I have been developing products with web technologies since 2011. I really love coding and delivering software with the right quality and I think it's important to balance business needs with engineering and architecture requirements. I enjoy working in innovative products that fit the users needs.

I strongly believe in continuous improvement. That's why I always seek opportunities to learn and embrace new challenges.

Gathered experience working on the full stack: aws cloud services, infrastructure, deployments, web and mobile application.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS:

- Cloud (AWS, Google).
- Contact Centers (AWS Amazon Connect, Lex, Contact Lens).
- Development of TPV in real time, with a payment platform(**OpenPay** API).
- Geolocation (api google maps v3).
- Angular, React (hooks, Redux), Vue (SPA, real time WebSockets, GraphQL).
- Mobile apps (ionic-angular framework, Flutter, React Native (iOs, Android).
- Linux / Unix server management, **Docker**, AWS-**EC2**, AWS-**EBS**, **ECS**, **EKS**.
- Api's Rest (NodeJS(express) or Python(Fastapi, Flask, Django) in AWS EC2 instances).
- Serverless microservices (AWS Lambda(NODE, PYTHON), AWS Api
 Gateway(Authorizers JsonWebTokens), AWS-SQS, AWS-SNS).
- PHP (Codeigniter, Laravel).
- .NET (ASP **C#** / Visual Basic).

- Design (normalization) and administration of SQL and NoSQL databases (SqlServer, MySql, Postgresql, MongoDB, DynamoDB).
- AWS (Lambda, Api Gateway, S3, SQS, Cloudwatch, RDS, EventBridge).
- **Unit tests** and Integration testing(**cypress**).
- CI/CD Using pipelines, automated deployments with jenkins to AWS.
- Using docker and dev-containers for development in VS-Code.

SKILLS

Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Time Management, Effective Communication, Teamwork, Resolving technical issues, Faster learner, Learn mindset, Coaching, Mentoring, Active listening, Abstract thinking, Honesty, Adaptability.

FRONT END:

- I have advanced knowledge on HTML, CSS3 and JavaScript (from ES1 to ES2020).
- I have used typescript in both the frontend and backend.
- CSS (Advanced knowledge): Flexbox, CSS Grid, responsive design (Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap).
- React Js (Advanced knowledge): Creating Class and Functional components, hooks, redux, hoc, styled-components.
- Angular (Advanced knowledge): Creating components, modules, services
 from angular cli, using redux or services to share the state, rxjs, protect the
 routes using guards.
- **Vue** (Advanced knowledge): Creating components, sharing the state using vuex(actions, mutations, getters, store).
- Using AWS S3 to deploy and cloudflare DNS.

BACK END:

Serverless microservices: (AWS Lambda(NODE, PYTHON), AWS Api
 Gateway(Authorizers), AWS-SQS).

- Python: Real time apps using socket.io, FastApi, Flask, Django, AWS
 Lambda(serverless).
- Node: Express (socket.io), AWS Lambda(Serverless).
- PHP: Laravel.
- Java: Spring, Spring Boot, Spring Data, Spring Security.
- Servers: Managing EC2 instances, VPS through SSH connection.

DATABASES:

SQL:

- MYSQL
- POSTGRESQL
- SQL SERVER
- AURORA (mysql postgresql)

NO SQL:

- Mongo db
- Dynamo DB

EXPERIENCE

LumSton

Cloud Operations | July 2022 at present.

Technologies:

- Frontend (Angular(typescrcipt), HTML, CSS, Tailwind).
- Backend (NodeJs, NestJs, Typescript, TypeOrm).
- Microservices serverless (AWS Lambda (NodeJs, Python), AWS ApiGateway, AWS RDS, AWS SNS, AWS DynamoDB, MongoDB, EventBridge, CloudWatch)
- Amazon Connect, Amazon Lex, Amazon Contact Lens (Create contact centers, programming the contact flow, recording calls to apply Al and analyze sentiments and improve the user experience)

Clip (Es la plataforma líder de pagos digitales y comercio)

Sr. Fullstack developer | October 2021 - June 2022.

Technologies:

- Front (JavaScript, Angular, React, HTML, CSS).
- Microservicios serverless (AWS Lambda (NodeJs, Python), AWS ApiGateway, AWS RDS, AWS DyanmosDB, MongoDB)
- AWS CloudFormation
- Git, GitHub, Jenkins
- Java, Spring Boot

Numina Mx

Full-stack developer | from December 2019 to November 2021.

- HTML, CSS(Responsive web design, Flexbox, CSS Grid)
- JavaScript (Angular, React(hooks), Vue)
- AWS (Lambda(Python3, NodeJs), Api Gateway, S3)
- Terraform, Packer
- Automated deployments to stage or production
- Unit Testing and code quality check(Sonarq)

I developed this website: https://www.numina.mx/ using react, styled-components, only css, without using UI libraries.

Envíoclick

Full-stack developer | from April 2019 to December 2019.

- Migrate application made in (Laravel, vue is) to Microservices
- JavaScript (Angular, React(hooks), Vue from laravel monolithic app)
- AWS (Lambda(Python3, NodeJs), Api Gateway, S3)
- Correction of bugs and development of features for app in Angular
- Automated deployments to stage or production
- Unit Testing and code quality check(Sonarq)

I developed this website: https://www.envioclick.com/mx using react, styled-components

Copiloto Satelital de Grupo Michelin (Ciudad de México)

Full-stack developer | from Mayo 2018 to April 2019.

- Design and development of a multiplatform application (ionic-angular), currently for android available in the PlayStore (Back-end / Front-end, store publication)
- .Net webApi (apiRestFul), NodeJS.
- SqlServer (Stored procedure)
- Git, BitBucket
- Bug fixes and improvements to the vehicle monitoring platform with GPS
- WebServices, WCF (.net, asp, C#, VB, SQL Server)
- Microservices (NodeJS, MongoDB(mongoose), SQL Server)

Mx-Race (Ciudad de México)

Developer | from December 2015 to April 2018.

- Design and development of an electronic timing system (.NET, SQL Server)
- Web Platform (html5, css3, js, bootstrap)), publication of results in real time (WebServices PHP)
- Design, development and implementation of an Enrollment System for athletic races charged to a credit / debit card
- Development of registration platforms for employees of private sports races (Grupo BAL, NISSAN Unbreakable, Deloitte, Grupo DESC - KUO, Dupont, Sagarpa, GEEP, BANXICO, Metlife).

https://www.mx-race.com/eventos/, https://time-mx.com/misinscripciones/, https://time-mx.com/resultados/unbreakable/2018/veracruz/

EDUCATION

Lic. Sistemas Computarizados e Informática

Universidad Loyola del Pacífico, ULP. (Grade point average: 9.1) (AUGUST 2006 - FEBRUARY 2011 - En proceso de titulación)

Address: Avenida Heroico Colegio Militar s/n, Acapulco Guerrero.

High School

Colegio de Bachilleres #24 (AUGUST 2003 - June 2006)

Address: Plan de los Amates, Acapulco Guerrero.